Guide to the Robert T. Jones Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Robert T. Jones papers
1912-1996
SC0576
Jones, Robert T. (Robert Thomas), 1910-
23 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Biography / Administrative History
Robert T. Jones, one of the premier theoretical aerodynamicists of the twentieth century, was a research scientist with NASA, and its predecessor NACA, from 1934 until his retirement in 1982, when he joined the Stanford faculty as a consulting professor in aeronautics. He is best known for developing the theory of swept and delta wings. He was elected to the National Academy of Arts and Sciences, the National Academy of Engineering, and the National Academy of Sciences. Among his other interests were blood flow dynamics, telescopes, and violins. He died in 1999.
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers of R. T. Jones include research notes and drawings, correspondence, patents, articles, reports, photographs, and other materials.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in the following series:
Series I: Aeronautical Files
Series II: Aeronautical Files: Swept Wing Original Papers
Series III: Publications and Reprints
Series IV: Telescopes and Optics
Series V: Violins and Acoustics
Series VI: General Files
Series VII: Videocassettes
Series VIII: Oversize Materials
Series IX: Additional Materials
Access Terms
Acoustical engineering.; Aerodynamics.; Aerofoils.; Aerospace engineering.; Airplanes--Wings.; Telescopes--Design and construction.; Violin--Construction.
Collection Contents
- Aeronautical Files, Series I
  This series includes drafts of Jones' autobiography "Learning the hard way: recollections of an aeronautical engineer."
  - Abbott, Ira H. and Harry Greenberg. Determination of Laminar Boundary Layer and Chordwise Distribution of Skin Friction on the NACA 27-212 Airfoil, November 1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abzug, M. J. Fuel Slosh in Skewed Tanks. Journal of Guidance, Control, and Dynamcis, Nov. 19, No. 5, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ackeret, Jakob, "Uber exakte Losungen der Stokes-Navier-Gleichungen. .", 1952 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Aerodynamics - miscellaneous figures (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Aerodynamics notebook (1) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Aerodynamics notebook (2) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Aerodynamics notebook (3) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Aerodynamics notebook (4) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Aerodynamics notebook (5) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Aerodynamics notebook (6) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Aerodynamics notebook (7) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Aerodynamics of wings at high speed - galley proofs (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Aeroelastic characteristics - notes and typescript of article (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Aeroelastic Stability and Control of an Oblique Wing," galleys (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Airfoil history, 1978, 1992-95 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Airfoil parameters (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Airfoil shapes, Data for (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Airfoil shapes, misc. text and drawings (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Airfoils and low Reynolds numbers, 1950-86 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Airplane scale, L / D weight (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Airship - research notes, tables (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Airship - sources, 1930, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - All wing SST - notebook (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Allen, H. Julian and Edward W. Perkins. Study of Effects of Viscosity on Flow Over Slender Inclined Bodies of Revolution. NACA Report 1048, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Althaus, Dieter. Profilpolaren fur den medellflug. ca. 1983 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1995-96 - mostly re nomination of Carlene Hutchins (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics (AIAA) - re nominations for AIAA Fellow, 1986-96 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - American Physical Society - Fluid Dynamics Prize, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Ames astronomy - notes and typescript paper (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Ames astronomy - photographs (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "Analysis of Accelerated Motion in the Theory of Relativity," paper to be presented to Nature Magazine - typescript drafts (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "Analysis of Accelerated Motion in the Theory of Relativity," paper to be presented to Nature Magazine - photostats for figures and one photograph (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Angle of climb (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Argus experiment (lecture at Foothill College), 1959-60 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Aspect ratio correction for hinge moments - Doris Cohen's file, 1942-46 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Asymmetrical wing, includes various articles by Jones and one photograph, 1972-74 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Atmosphere: International units, 1957-90 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Baldwin, B. S. and H. Lomax. Thin Layer Approximation and Algebraic Model for Separated Turbulent Flows. AIAA 16th Aerospace Sciences Meeting, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Beech A24R Sierra - plans (from FLIGHT INTERNATIONAL) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Beech PD345 Drawings, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Beech PD345 Figures and charts, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Beech Aircraft PD345 - Memo, figures, etc., 1982-83 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Beech PD345 Stability (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Beech airfoil (Airfoil Development and Selection for the PD345 by Tom Zickuhr, 1983) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Beech airfoils - graphs (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Bergman, Stefan. Four reprints, one technical report, 1946-58 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Birds - articles, notes, correspondence, 1970-93 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Black, R. L., et. al. Wind Tunnel Investigation of an Oblique Wing Transport Model at Mach Numbers between 0.6 and 1.4. NASA report, July 1975 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Boeing 707, 747, 2707, etc. - articles (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Boeing Company, Oblique Wing Transonic Transport Configuration Development Final Report, January 1977 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Boeing: Concord - articles, 1974-91 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Boeing scale model (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Boeing vs Beech figures (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Boeing/Douglas - articles, correspondence, reports re oblique all-wing designs; includes correspondence with Peter Rudolph and Frank D. Neumann, 1991-96 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Boundary layer: memo and figures, 1970-71 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Boundary layer - notebook (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Boynton, John H. Experimental Study of an Ablating sphere with Hydromagnetic Effect Included. Journal of the Aero/Space Sciences, April 1960 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Brocher, Eric F. On Similar solutions for Strong Blast Waves and Their Application to Steady Hypersonic Flow. Journal of Aerospace Sciences, June 1962 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Busemann, Adolf. "Infinitesimal Conical Supersonic Flow,", 1943 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Business jets - data, 1977-92 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Canard - articles, 1978-88 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Canard - notes, figures, graphs, text (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Carrier, G. P. On the Conformal Mapping of Airfoils, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Catalogs (aircraft parts, lab equipment) (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Chapman, Dean R. - memorial tribute (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Circular and delta planforms (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - CLASB (Citizens League Against the Sonic Boom): noise; includes letters from Ben Pinkel and Bo Lundberg, 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Cloud dancer plane - plans, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Cmq definition - notes and letter from Charles McCutchen, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Cole, J. D. Acceleration of Slender Bodies of Revolution Through Sonic Velocity. OSR Technical Note 54-55, January 1954 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Commercial aircraft (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Complex velocity functions and other subjects - notebook (with index) (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Compressible flow tables (1947 NACA publication) (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Computer print-outs [11-601-1], 1973 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Congressional Record and other government publicatons, 1968, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Conical flow and other subjects - notebook (with index) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Conical flow tables (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Conical flow tables - original masters (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: reviews and comments on papers, 1978-81 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Crystal Eagle award (Aero Club of No. Calif.), 1992-93 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Daedalus aircraft - letter, drawings, xerox of photo, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - de Silva, Brian - correspondence and notes, 1991-95 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Deflection - notes, 1992-93 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Delta wing - "Characteristics of an Airplane with a Large Angle of Sweepback," (Box 6, Folder 10.1)
  - Dive speed: wing bend: ailerons (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Douglas SST tests, 1988-90 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Early swept wing calculations (Box 6, Folder 12.1)
  - "Economy of Flight at Supersonic Speeds" (Berkeley talk) - typescript and figures, Nov. 1948 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Electric flight, articles about, 1983-84 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Elementary Aerodynamics, typescript (1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Elementary Aerodynamics, typescript (2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Elementary Aerodynamics, typescript and figures, with letter from Princeton University Press, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Elementary Aerodynamics - Figures (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Ellipse drag, CD/CL 2 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Elliptic functions and integrals (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Energy - articles about and two letters by Jones to politicians, 1977-80 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Engines, small (includes 1 photograph) (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Ercoupe: data re sale of aircraft, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Executive jets: scale (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Experimental design, includes letter to David L. Kohlman re problem in Kohlman's modification of aircraft, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Fahlin, Ole, biographical articles, 1982, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Falco kits, 1979-84 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Fay, James A. and Edward Lekawa. Ignition of Combustible Gases by Convergin Shock Waves. Journal of Applied Physics, March 1956 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Feistel, T. W. A Method for Localizing Wing Flow Separation at Stall to Alleviate Spin Entry Tendencies. AIAA Aircraft Systems and Technology Conference, Aug. 1978 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Figures (extra), possibly for "subsonic aero" (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Fins (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Flying Circus: assorted items, including 2 photographs, re Curtiss Jenny aircraft (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Flying tips, 1974-79 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Flying wing 1990; includes drafts of "Supersonic Flying Wing," "Supersonic Air Transportation", and "Trans-Pacific Supersonic Transport" (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Flying wing figures; includes 1 photograph (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - "Flying wing SST for the Pacific" - galleys (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Flying wing stability (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Flying wing - viewgraphs and 1 photograph of model (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Fourier series drag (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Friedman, Morris D. and Doris Cohen. Arrangement of Fusiform Bodies to Reduce the Wave Drag at Supersonic Speeds. NACA Report 1236, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Frost, Richard C. Body Modifications Which Make Linear Theory Solutions More Exact. Convair Report No. MR-A-1245, July 1960 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Fuel economy, 1973-75 and undted (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Galloway et. al. "Large Capacity Oblique All-Wing Transport Aircraft," Transportation Beyond 2000: Engineering Design for the Future, September 26-28, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Garabedian airfoils (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Garabedian, P. R. Three reprints, 1952-53 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Gilbarg, D. and M. Shiffman. On Bodies Achieving Extreme Values of the Critical Mach Number, I. Journal of Rational Mechanics and Analysis, March 1954 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Glass wings; includes 1946 NACA technical note no. 1046 "Preliminary wind-tunnel investigation at low speed of stability and control characteristics of swept-back wings" (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Goodyear references (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Goodyear Report (airship hulls) - correspondence, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Goodyear Report (airship hulls) - drafts (1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Goodyear Report (airship hulls) - drafts (2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Goodyear Report (airship hulls) - final copy with slides, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Goodyear Report (airship hulls) - miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Gortler - notes (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Graham, E. W. "The Calculation of Minimum Supersonic Drag by Solution of an Equivalent Two-Dimensional Potential Problem, ", December 1956 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Gravitational fields, waves - articles, 1912, 1948-73 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Gravitational fields, waves - correspondence, notes, 1960-83 and undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Ground effect (includes letter from Kevin A. Cameron, 1992) (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Guggenheim lecture; Sears lecture [draft of text and Jones'NASA publication Improving the Efficiency of Smaller Transport Aircraft], 1984 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Gusts (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Harned, Malcolm, "Margin of Safety - Philosophy of Design," 1977, and one letter 1980 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Hayes, Wallace D. - articles, 1954-68 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - HIGH SPEED WING THEORY, Pages from (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Historical talk for AIAA,: manuscript, newsletter, and photo illustrations re interplanetary travel, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Hollmann, Martin: airship LEAP, correspondence and report, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Hollmann, Martin - correspondence, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Hollmann, Martin - drawings for Celair "Midget" 1991; letter, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Hopkins, Edward J. et. al. Experimental Aerodynamic Characteristics of Low-Aspect Ratio Swept and Oblique Wings at Mach Numbers Between 0.6 and 1.4. NASA Technical Memorandum, November 1973 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Hot materials - articles (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Human-Powered Flight Symposium - papers, one letter from E. Eugene Larrabee, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Hydrofoils - articles and notes (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - ICAS (International Council of the Aeronautical Sciences), Madrid - paper, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - ICAS, Toulouse, France - papers, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Innovative Aerodynamics Workshop: memoranda and papers, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Integrals (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Integrals - notebook (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Jacobs, Eastman N. Preliminary Report on Laminar-Flow Airfoils and New Methods Adopted for Airfoil and Boundary-Layer Investigations. NACA, June 1939 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Japan, 1987 trip; includes color snapshots (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Jones, David - correspondence, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Joukowsky airfoils - articles (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Joukowsky airfoils - text, figures, one letter from Dan M. Somers, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Journal of the Aeronautical Sciences, Vol. 25 No. 4, April 1958 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Katzen, Elliott D. "Idealized Wings and Wing-Bodies at a Mach Number of 3." NACA Technical Note 4361, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Kemp, Nelson H. On the Lift and Circulation of Airfoils in Some Unsteady-Flow Problems. Journal of the Aeronautical Sciences, Oct. 1952 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Kinetic theory - notebook (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Kites - text, figures, other articles, photographs, and 1 letter re publication of article, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Kogan, M. N. - articles, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - KR-2 plane - plans, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Kroo, Ilan - articles (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Kuchmann, Dietrich. Stream Function and Velocity Compenents for Frequesntly Used Singularities, with Tables; and The Aerodymanic Design of Aircraft (photocopies) (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Kuessner, H. G. Four reprints, 1940-55, and mimeographed equations for public lecture April 9, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Kutta condition - readers'forum in J of A Sciences, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Langhans and Flechner, "Wind-Tunnel Investigation at Mach Numbers From 0.25 to 1.01 of a Transport Configuration Designed to Cruise at Near-sonic Speeds." 1972 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Langley: papers, correspndence, and photos, 1986-90 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Larrabee, Eugene - letter and resume, 1994-96 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Lateral control (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Lateral control - NACA technical notes and reports, 1933, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Lateral stability [oblique all wing] (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Lateral stability [tailless glilder], includes 1923 article (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Learning the Hard Way: Recollections of an Aeronautical Engineer - various typescript drafts (Adventures in Aeronautics) (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Learning the Hard Way: Recollections of an Aeronautical Engineer II- various typescript drafts (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Learning the Hard Way - final copy (2) (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Learning the Hard Way - figures (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Learning the Hard Way - original illustrations (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Lee, Godfrey H. - correspondence, 1970-80, and articles, 1960-92 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Legendre functions (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Letter to Aerospace America, circa 1988 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Levey, H. C. and P. E. Wynter. The Circular Wing and Related Problems. Proceedings of the Royal Society, A, volume 268, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Liebeck, Robet H. Deisgn of Subsonic Airfoils for High Lift. Journal of Aircraft, September 1978 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Lift / Drag, Charts for (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Lift / Drag Data Plots [W45 Fo B], 1972 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Lift / Drag Data Plots [W50 Fo B], 1972 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Lift / Drag Data Plots [W55 Fo B], 1972 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Lift / Drag Data Plots [W60 Fo B], 1972 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Lift / Drag Data Plots, combined phases 1, 2, 3 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Lift / drag PMPG tables (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Lift / Drag, power required (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Lift / drag test results [unspecified project] (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Light airplanes, includes plans and phots (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Light airplanes - articles (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Light airplanes - articles re building them (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Light airplanes - NACA technical notes and reports, 1924-35 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Lighthill, James - correspondence and articles, 1945, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Lin, Shao-Chi. Cylindrical Shock Waves Produced by Instantaeous Energy Release. Journal of Applied Physics, January 1954 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Load and deflection (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Longitudinal stability - notebook (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Lorce, Lee. Two reprints, 1952, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Low Reynolds numbers airfoils (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Low speed airfoils (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - M = 1+ Transport (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Maneuvers (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Mars - notebook (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Materials - C.F. glass, etc. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - McCornack, Mark - letter and internet print-offs, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - McCune, J. E. and W. R. Sears. On Magnetohydrodynamic Channel Flow. Journal of the Aero/Space Sciences, Feb. 1960 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Meyers, Leroy F. Two reprints, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - MHD - notebook (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Microwave sailplane - reports, 1978-79 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Miles per gallon 1973 and undated (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Miles per gallon 1975 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - "Minimizing the Induced Drag" - tss of article (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Minimum drag - figures (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Minimum drag - miscellaneous notes (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Minimum Drag of Thin Wings at Supersonic Speed According to Kogan's Theory - various drafts (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - "Minimum drag of wings at supersonic speed," paper presented at the Symposium on Extremal Problems in Aerodynamcis, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence [found loose or misplaced in folders], 1936, 1958-98 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous drawings (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous formulas (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous notes [loose in original box] (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous solutions/inventions, 1967-97 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Mises, R. v. and M. Schiffer. On Bergman's Integration Method in Two-Dimensional Compressible Fluid Flow. Advances in Applied Mathematics, Vol 1, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - MIT studies (business jets), 1978 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Motorcycle airplane (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - NACA: Index of Technical Notes on Aeronautical Research and Index of Reports on Aeronautical Research, 1940 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - National Academy of Engineering, 1995-98 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - National Academy of Sciences (1 of 2) (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - National Academy of Sciences (2 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - National Research Council - misc. correspondence, 1990-91 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Nicholas-Beazley - text, articles, photos (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Nicholas-Beazley - correspondence in response to Jones'article, 1993-95 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Nicholas-Beazley - Jack Kennedy articles and correspondence, 1975-91 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Nickel, Karl. "Solution of Minimum Problems of the Airfoil Theory." NACA, 1951 [both German and English versions] (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Nikolskij, A. A. "Some Flows of an Ideal Fluid Originating with Separation and Their Consideration from the Standpoint of Boundary Layer Theory." (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Nomination forms (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - "Non-Rigid Airship Hulls; Stability of Shape Under the Action of Air Forces" - typescript (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Notebook, unlabeled (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Notes on chapter IX (Minimum drag of thin wings), and letter from Science re publication, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Notes, unlabelled [originally preceeded "subsonic aero"] (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Notes, various [original binder was labeled "tensor"] (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Oblique all-wing airplane - article, graphs, notes [original name of folder=drag divergence] (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Oblique All-wing airplane - drafts, figures, photo of model in wind tunnel, Dec. 1991 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Oblique all-wing airplane - text, figures, press release, 1991 and undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Oblique all-wing - Ames meetings (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Oblique all-wing - Ames reports (1 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Oblique all-wing - Ames reports (2 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Oblique all-wing cruise mach & capacity study. Final briefing at NASA-Ames, Nov. 17, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Oblique all-wing: illustration (color and B/W photos of artist's rendering) (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Oblique all-wing - misc. correspondence, 1972, 1991-94 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Oblique all-wing - planforms (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Oblique all-wing project - assorted documents (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Oblique all-wing project meeting, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Oblique flying wing - article, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Oblique flying wing - scale model (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Oblique wing - articles, reports, illustrations and photographs, 1986-87 and undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Oblique wing - 11 ft. wind tunnel tests (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Oblique wing aircraft - NASA report 1978, reprint 1979 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Oblique wing - Ames tests, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Oblique wing - data, Ames meeting, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Oblique wing glider, instruction sheet (NASA Ames publiction), 1977 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Oblique Wing Patent (Box 17, Folder 9.1)
  - Offner, Franklin: correspondence re Draper Prize, 1988-89 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Old airplanes - articles, four photographs (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Old airplanes - Curtiss Tanager; includes photograph and letter from Henry V. Borst, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Operational calculus - notes, 1941 and undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Operator series - notes (Box 17, Folder 14)